<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<GateDocument version="3">
<!-- The document's features-->

<GateDocumentFeatures>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">gate.SourceURL</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">file:/opt/brat-v1.3_Crunchy_Frog/data/19msmt/BlueSky/DA42-POH--has-failure-mode/DA42-POH-44.txt</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">MimeType</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">text/plain</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">docNewLineType</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">LF</Value>
</Feature>
</GateDocumentFeatures>
<!-- The document content area with serialized nodes -->

<TextWithNodes> <Node id="1"/>Airplane Description                                                        DA 42 AFM 
7.9    POWER PLANT 
7.9.1  ENGINES, GENERAL 
There are two TAE125 engines installed, which have the following principal specifications: 
   -  Liquid-cooled four-cylinder four-stroke Diesel-cycle engine with wet sump 
      lubrication 
   -  Inline construction 
   -  Common rail direct injection 
   -  Propeller speed reducing gear 1:1.69 
   -  Digital Engine Control with Integrated Propeller Governor (separate oil system) 
   -  Turbo charger with Intercooler 
Displacement: 
      TAE 125-01 engine:                                        1689 cm³ (103 in³) 
      TAE 125-02-99 engine (MÄM 42-198 carried out):            1991 cm³ (121.5 in³) 
Max. power:                99 kW (135 DIN-HP) at 2300 RPM at sea level and ISA 
Max. continuous power:     99 kW (135 DIN-HP) at 2300 RPM at sea level and ISA 
The indications for monitoring important engine parameters during operation are integrated 
within the Garmin G1000 display. Each engine can only be operated with the ENGINE 
MASTER switch ON. Each engine has an own ECU (Engine Control Unit) which receives 
its electrical power from the generator when at least one engine is running. When both 
engines are at standstill, the ECU receives its electrical power from the battery. 
  Page 7 - 28    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 331-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                       Airplane Description 
7.9.2  PROPELLER 
Two mt-Propeller MTV-6-A-C-F/CF187-129 hydraulically regulated 3-bladed constant 
speed feathering <Node id="1676"/>propellers<Node id="1686"/> are installed. Each propeller has wood composite <Node id="1736"/>blades<Node id="1742"/> with 
fiber-reinforced plastic <Node id="1774"/>coating<Node id="1781"/> and stainless steel <Node id="1802"/>edge<Node id="1806"/> cladding; in the region of the 
propeller hub the leading edge is coated with adhesive PU foil. These blades combine 
the lowest weight whilst minimizing vibration. 
Propeller Control 
The propeller pitch control system is integrated into the engine. The pitch is controlled 
automatically by the <Node id="2104"/>ECU<Node id="2107"/>. To change the blade pitch angle gearbox oil is pumped into 
the <Node id="2173"/>propeller hub<Node id="2186"/>. The oil pressure is regulated by an electrically operated <Node id="2246"/>valve<Node id="2251"/>, the 
<Node id="2258"/>governor valve<Node id="2272"/>, which is controlled by the ECU. Increasing the oil pressure leads to a 
decrease of pitch and a higher RPM. Decreasing the pressure leads to higher pitch and 
a lower RPM. 
Depending on the power setting the propeller pitch is adjusted such that the required RPM 
will be obtained as shown in the following diagram. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Page 7 - 29 
----------------------- Page 332-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                            DA 42 AFM 
<Node id="2823"/>Pressure Accumulator<Node id="2843"/>: 
The pressure accumulator is a nitrogen oil type. It is connected to the gearbox oil circuit 
via an <Node id="2946"/>electric valve<Node id="2960"/> at the <Node id="2968"/>accumulator<Node id="2979"/>, which is operated with the <Node id="3008"/>ENGINE MASTER 
switch<Node id="3029"/>. 
When the ENGINE MASTER switch is set to ON the valve is opened. When the engine 
is running, the accumulator is filled with oil at a pressure of approximately 20 bar (290 PSI). 
During engine operation the accumulator makes sure that enough oil pressure is available 
even if the oil feed by the <Node id="3328"/>gearbox oil pump<Node id="3344"/> is decreasing due to negative acceleration. 
The hydraulic pressure keeps the propeller pitch angle below the start lock position, or 
moves the propeller blades beyond the start lock position. 
Feathering: 
To feather the propeller the engine must be shut down with the appropriate ENGINE 
MASTER switch. This will open the <Node id="3670"/>electric governor valve<Node id="3693"/>. All oil will flow back from the 
propeller hub, allowing the blades to move into the feathered pitch position. At the same 
time the electric valve at the pressure accumulator closes, and the oil pressure is restored 
in the accumulator.  
Feathering is only possible at propeller speeds above 1300 RPM. 
                                         CAUTION 
               If the engine is shut down below an RPM of 1300 the propeller 
               pitch remains below the start lock position. In this case the 
               speed must be increased to increase the propeller RPM. 
  Page 7 - 30    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                         Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 333-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                         Airplane Description 
Unfeathering: 
To unfeather the propeller, the associated ENGINE MASTER switch must be set to ON. 
This will open the electric valve at the pressure accumulator. The pressure stored in the 
accumulator will move the propeller blades into a low pitch position. As soon as the 
propeller starts turning and the gearbox oil operates, the accumulator will be refilled. 
Ground Operation: 
                                        CAUTION 
               Operation on the ground at high RPM should be avoided as 
               far as possible, as the blades could suffer stone damage. For 
               this reason a suitable site for engine runs should be selected, 
               where there are no loose stones or similar items. 
                                       WARNING 
                           Never move the propeller by hand. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                       Page 7 - 31 
----------------------- Page 334-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                             DA 42 AFM 
7.9.3  OPERATING CONTROLS 
<Node id="5610"/>POWER Lever<Node id="5621"/> 
Engine performance is controlled by a power lever for each engine. Both power levers 
are situated on the large center console. 'Front' and 'rear' are defined in relation to the 
direction of flight. 
Each power lever is used to set the desired engine power LOAD (%) 
                  Lever forward (MAX)       =  Full power 
                  Lever to rear (IDLE)      =  Idle 
A separate ECU for each engine controls manifold pressure, injected fuel quantity and 
propeller speed according to the desired engine power preselected with the power lever. 
If the power lever is in a low power position - as for a landing approach - while the landing 
gear is retracted, an aural warning alerts the pilot to the retracted landing gear. If installed 
a CHECK GEAR caution is indicated on the PFD additionally. 
A <Node id="6434"/>propeller governor<Node id="6452"/>, which is controlled by the <Node id="6481"/>ECU<Node id="6484"/>, is flanged onto the front of each 
engine. The propeller governor oil circuit is supplied with oil by the <Node id="6592"/>gearbox oil pump<Node id="6608"/> (also 
see Section 7.9.2 - PROPELLER). A loss of oil pressure leads to a feathering of the 
propeller <Node id="6711"/>blades<Node id="6717"/>, thus allowing continuation of the flight according to 3.9.3 - DEFECTIVE 
PROPELLER RPM REGULATING SYSTEM. 
                                          CAUTION 
                Following governor failure the RPM should be adjusted using 
               the power lever. Every effort should be made not to exceed 
               2300 RPM. 
  Page 7 - 32    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                         Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 335-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                         Airplane Description 
                                        CAUTION 
               The power lever should be moved slowly, in order to avoid 
               over-speeding and excessively rapid RPM changes. The light 
               wooden propeller blades produce more rapid RPM changes 
               than metal blades. 
                                       WARNING 
               It is possible that the propeller blades remain in the position 
               of highest pitch in case of a malfunction of the engine control 
               unit. In this case the reduced engine performance should be 
               taken into consideration. 
ELECT. MASTER 
The electric master switch has two positions: 
OFF    disconnecting battery power 
ON     connecting battery power to the power distribution system 
ENGINE MASTER 
Each engine can only be cranked with its ENGINE MASTER switched to ON. When 
activated, the ENGINE MASTER provides the power supply for the preheat system, the 
unfeathering accumulator valve and the engine itself. To shut down the engine the 
appropriate ENGINE MASTER is switched to OFF. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                       Page 7 - 33 
----------------------- Page 336-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                             DA 42 AFM 
START 
Turning START key switch to the left starts the LH engine. Turning it to the right side starts 
the RH engine. 
ECU SWAP 
There are two ECU SWAP switches, one for each engine. For normal operation both 
switches are set to AUTOMATIC. Each engine is controlled by its ECU A. In case of a 
failure of the active engine control unit (ECU) there should be an automatic switch-over 
to the appropriate ECU B. If the automatic switch over fails, switch over can be done 
manually by switching to ECU B. This procedure should only be applied in an emergency. 
ECU TEST 
There are two ECU TEST buttons, one for each engine. Depending on the position of 
the power lever and the engine speed, the ECU TEST button has two different functions. 
Power lever at IDLE and RPM below approximately 900: 
    By pushing and holding the button until the end of the procedure, the self-test of each 
    engine control unit is started. The procedure is possible on the ground as well as during 
    flight, but only if the power lever is in the IDLE position. Otherwise the test will not start. 
    During the procedure the ECU performs a switch from ECU A to ECU B with the 
    propeller cycling. The propeller RPM is monitored automatically by the ECU. When 
    switching from one ECU to the other, a slight shake of the engine may occur. Finally 
    the ECU switches back from ECU B to ECU A. After that both caution lights must 
    extinguish and the engine must run without a change. 
Power lever above IDLE, or RPM above approximately 900: 
    If an ECU A or ECU B caution message is displayed, the ECU TEST button can be 
    pressed for more than 2 seconds to reset the message. The reset is possible only once, 
    and only in case of system faults of minor criticality. 
  Page 7 - 34    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                         Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 337-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                          Airplane Description 
Alternate Air 
In the event of power loss because of icing or blocking of the <Node id="10708"/>air filter<Node id="10718"/>, there is the 
possibility of drawing air from the <Node id="10770"/>engine compartment<Node id="10788"/>. The ALTERNATE AIR operating 
lever which serves both engines simultaneously is located under the instrument panel 
to the right of the center console. To open the alternate air source the lever is pulled to 
the rear. Normally, the alternate air source is closed with the lever in the forward position. 
Placard on the lever, forward position: 
                                    ALTERNATE AIR 
Placard on the lever, visible when lever is in the rearward position: 
                                    ALTERNATE AIR 
                                             ON 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Page 7 - 35 
----------------------- Page 338-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                       DA 42 AFM 
7.9.4  ENGINE INSTRUMENTS 
The engine instruments are displayed on the Garmin G1000 MFD. Also refer to Section 
7.13.3 - MULTI FUNCTION DISPLAY (MFD). Indications for the LH engine are on the 
left side, indications for the RH engine are on the right side. 
       Default page               Display when pushing          Display when pushing 
       Engine                     the SYSTEM button             the FUEL button 
  Page 7 - 36    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 339-----------------------
DA 42 AFM                                                       Airplane Description 
                                        NOTE 
             The figure on previous page is a general demonstration of 
             a typical G1000 MFD to show the different display modes. 
             The pictured engine instrument markings may not stringently 
             agree with the current engine limitations of the DA 42. 
                                        NOTE 
             The fuel calculations on the FUEL CALC portion do not use 
             the airplane’s fuel quantity indicators. The values shown are 
             numbers  which are calculated from  the last fuel quantity 
             update done by the pilot and actual fuel flow data. Therefore, 
             the endurance and range data is for information only, and 
             must not be used for flight planning. 
       Designation                       Indication                       Unit 
LOAD %                        Available power                              % 
RPM                           Propeller RPM                               1/min 
FUEL FLOW                     Fuel flow                                 US gal/hr 
OIL TEMP                      Engine oil temperature                       °C 
OIL PRES                      Oil pressure                                 bar 
COOLANT TEMP                  Coolant temperature                          °C 
FUEL TEMP                     Fuel temperature                             °C 
FUEL QTY GAL                  Fuel quantity                              US gal 
VOLTS                         Volts                                        V 
AMPS                          Ampères                                      A 
GEARBOX                       Gearbox temperature                          °C 
 Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Page 7 - 37 
----------------------- Page 340-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                            DA 42 AFM 
7.9.5  FUEL SYSTEM 
General 
  Page 7 - 38    Rev. 8     15-Dec-2017                  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 341-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                          Airplane Description 
Fuel is stored in the <Node id="14482"/>tanks<Node id="14487"/> which are located in the <Node id="14513"/>wings<Node id="14518"/>. 
Normally fuel for the <Node id="14543"/>right engine<Node id="14555"/> is taken from the right wing <Node id="14585"/>main tank<Node id="14594"/> and for the left 
engine from the left wing main tank. 
On each engine fuel is injected with high pressure directly into the <Node id="14720"/>cylinders<Node id="14729"/>. The <Node id="14735"/>injection 
nozzles<Node id="14753"/> (one per cylinder) are supplied with fuel by the <Node id="14803"/>common rail<Node id="14814"/>. Pressure inside the 
rail is generated by a high pressure pump which receives fuel from a <Node id="14906"/>low pressure pump<Node id="14923"/>. 
Depending on the power setting the rail pressure is controlled by the <Node id="14996"/>ECU<Node id="14999"/> through an 
<Node id="15012"/>electric valve<Node id="15026"/>. Both pumps are powered mechanically by the engine. Fuel that is not 
injected is fed back into the appropriate wing tank. 
Both sides of the fuel system are interconnected by <Node id="15203"/>crossfeed lines<Node id="15218"/>.  
In each engine <Node id="15237"/>nacelle<Node id="15244"/> an <Node id="15248"/>auxiliary fuel tank<Node id="15267"/> may be installed (OÄM 42-056 carried out). 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Page 7 - 39 
----------------------- Page 342-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                           DA 42 AFM 
Fuel Selector Valves 
For each engine one <Node id="15587"/>fuel selector valve<Node id="15606"/> is provided. The <Node id="15624"/>control levers<Node id="15638"/> for the f<Node id="15648"/>uel selector 
valves<Node id="15668"/> are situated on the center console behind the power levers. The positions are ON, 
CROSSFEED and OFF. During normal operation each engine takes the fuel from the 
tank on the same side as the engine. When CROSSFEED is selected, the engine will 
draw fuel from the <Node id="15933"/>tank<Node id="15937"/> on the opposite side in order to extend range and keep fuel weight 
balanced during single engine operation. With the fuel selector valve both the feeding 
and the return line are switched. 
The desired position is reached by pulling the lever back. To reach the OFF position a 
safety  guard  must  be  twisted.  This  is  to  ensure  that  this  selection  is  not  made 
unintentionally. 
                                           NOTE 
               If one engine is inoperative the fuel selector valve for this 
               engine must be in the OFF position. 
                                        CAUTION 
               Do not operate with both fuel selector valves in CROSSFEED 
               position.  Do  not  take-off  with  a  fuel  selector  valve  in 
               CROSSFEED position. 
                                        CAUTION 
               Do not shut down an engine with the fuel selector valve. The 
               high pressure fuel pump can otherwise be damaged. 
  Page 7 - 40    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                         Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 343-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                          Airplane Description 
Scheme of the Fuel Selector Valve Positions: 
Possible  operating  modes  of  the  three  fuel  selector  valve  positions  are  outlined 
systematically  in  the  following  scheme.  The  Figures  below  show  fuel  flows  for  the 
RH engine (fuel flows LH are alike): 
Figure 1: 
Normal 
Operation 
Figure 2: 
CROSS- 
FEED 
Operation 
Figure 3: 
Shut-off 
Position 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Page 7 - 41 
----------------------- Page 344-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                         DA 42 AFM 
With the LH fuel selector valve in CROSSFEED position, the fuel from the RH tank is 
transferred to the LH engine. Depending on the position of the RH fuel selector valve, 
the RH tank then feeds both engines (as shown in Figure 4 below) or only the LH engine, 
when the fuel selector valve of the RH engine is in shut-off position (as shown in Figure 5 
below). 
              Figure 4: Fuel selector valve RH normal operation position, fuel selector 
                        valve LH CROSSFEED position 
              Figure 5: Fuel selector RH valve shut-off position, fuel selector valve LH 
                        CROSSFEED position 
  Page 7 - 42    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 345-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                              Airplane Description 
<Node id="18648"/>Main Fuel Tanks<Node id="18663"/> 
Each tank consists of three <Node id="18693"/>aluminum chambers<Node id="18710"/> which are connected by a <Node id="18736"/>flexible hose<Node id="18749"/>. 
The tank is filled through a <Node id="18781"/>filler<Node id="18787"/> in the outboard fuel chamber. Only four liter (1 US gal) 
of fuel in each wing are unusable, so that a total quantity of 94.6 liter (25 US gal) in each 
wing is usable. 
There are two <Node id="18972"/>tank vents<Node id="18982"/>. One includes a <Node id="18999"/>check valve<Node id="19010"/> with a capillary and one includes 
a <Node id="19048"/>relief pressure valve<Node id="19069"/>, which operates at 150 mbar (2 PSI) and allows fuel and air to flow 
to the outside with higher internal pressure. The relief pressure valve protects the tank 
against high pressure, if the tank was overfilled in case of an auxiliary fuel transfer failure. 
The check valve with <Node id="19349"/>capillary<Node id="19358"/> allows air to enter the tank but prevents flow of fuel to the 
outside. The capillary equalizes the air pressure during climb. The hose terminals are 
located on the underside of the wing, approximately 2 m (7 ft) from the wing tip. 
In each tank a <Node id="19608"/>coarse filter<Node id="19621"/> (finger filter) is fitted before the outlet. To allow draining of 
the tank, there is an <Node id="19711"/>outlet valve<Node id="19723"/> at its lowest point. 
At the lowest point in each side of the fuel system a fuel filter with a drain valve is installed. 
This drain valve can be used to remove water and sediment which has collected in the 
fuel system. The drain valves are fitted in each nacelle behind the <Node id="20000"/>firewall<Node id="20008"/>, approximately 
15 cm (0.56 ft) backward of the wing leading edge. 
Fuel Quantity Indication 
Two capacity probes measure the fuel quantity in each main tank. The indication is 
provided by the <Node id="20203"/>G1000<Node id="20208"/> flight display. Information about fuel consumption can be found 
in Chapter 5 - PERFORMANCE.  
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8         15-Dec-2017                          Page 7 - 43 
----------------------- Page 346-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                           DA 42 AFM 
<Node id="20540"/>Auxiliary Fuel Tanks<Node id="20560"/> (if installed) 
The auxiliary fuel tanks are optional equipment (OÄM 42-056). 
Description 
The auxiliary fuel tanks are installed in the rear section of the engine nacelles, above the 
wing main spars. Each auxiliary fuel tank has a <Node id="20795"/>filler cap<Node id="20805"/> located on the top surface of 
the nacelle. The additional fuel capacity is 52 liter (13.7 US gal) per side. The total fuel 
capacity (main fuel tanks and auxiliary fuel tanks) is 150.4 liter (39.7 US gal) per side. 
The fuel supply connection attaches to a <Node id="21064"/>finger filter<Node id="21077"/> mounted at the rear of the auxiliary 
fuel tank. Each auxiliary fuel tank has a <Node id="21158"/>fuel transfer pump<Node id="21176"/> which pumps fuel into the 
related main fuel tank. Upstream of the fuel transfer pump an <Node id="21266"/>inline filter<Node id="21279"/>, a <Node id="21283"/>solenoid valve<Node id="21297"/> 
and a <Node id="21305"/>check valve<Node id="21316"/> are installed. The valves prevent fuel from flowing back out of the main 
tank into the auxiliary tank. 
The <Node id="21426"/>vent line<Node id="21435"/> for the auxiliary fuel tank has a check valve with <Node id="21487"/>capillary.<Node id="21497"/> It allows air to 
enter the tank but prevents flow of fuel to the outside. The capillary equalizes the air 
pressure during climb. A <Node id="21631"/>fuel drain valve<Node id="21647"/> is located at the rear of each auxiliary tank. 
Operation 
Two <Node id="21711"/>FUEL TRANSFER switches<Node id="21733"/> in the cockpit are used to activate the <Node id="21774"/>fuel transfer pumps<Node id="21793"/> 
and to open the <Node id="21811"/>solenoid valves<Node id="21826"/>. The <Node id="21832"/>switches<Node id="21840"/> are located behind the <Node id="21864"/>elevator trim wheel<Node id="21883"/> 
on the center console. Both switches are intended to be used simultaneously to prevent 
the airplane from additional lateral imbalance. The fuel transfer pump pumps the fuel from 
the <Node id="22069"/>auxiliary fuel tank<Node id="22088"/> into the related <Node id="22106"/>main fuel tank<Node id="22120"/>. Fuel level switches shut this pump 
and the related solenoid valves off automatically, if the auxiliary fuel tank is empty or if 
the main fuel tank is full. During operation of the pumps an advisory alert on the <Node id="22335"/>Garmin 
G1000<Node id="22348"/> indicates that the fuel transfer is in progress. 
If the auxiliary fuel tank is empty, a caution alert appears on the Garmin G1000. In this 
case the fuel pumps must be switched OFF. 
  Page 7 - 44    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 347-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                             Airplane Description 
When one fuel transfer pump is defective, the fuel stored in the related auxiliary fuel tank 
is not available. For use of the remaining fuel pump refer to Section 4B.11 - L/R FUEL 
TRANSFER FAIL. The flight plan must be amended accordingly. 
The fuel transfer pumps and the solenoid valves are electrically connected to the LH main 
bus  and  protected  by  a  5  A  or  7.5  A  circuit  breaker,  if  no  ice  protection  system 
(OÄM 42-053) is installed.  
Otherwise the fuel transfer pumps and the ice protection system (OÄM 42-053) are 
protected by a 10 A circuit breaker. The fuel transfer pumps are additionally protected 
by a 7 A inline fuse. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                          Page 7 - 45 
----------------------- Page 348-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                           DA 42 AFM 
Alternate Means for Fuel Quantity 
Indication for the Fuel Tank: 
The  alternate  means  for  fuel  quantity 
indication allows the fuel quantity in the 
tank to be determined during the preflight 
inspection. It functions according to the 
principle  of  communicating  containers. 
The <Node id="23946"/>fuel quantity measuring device<Node id="23976"/> has 
a recess which fits the airfoil of the <Node id="24021"/>wing<Node id="24025"/> 
in front of the fuel <Node id="24048"/>tank drain<Node id="24058"/>, which lies 
approximately 10 cm (4 in) outboard of 
the engine nacelle. The <Node id="24136"/>metal connector<Node id="24151"/> 
is pressed against the drain of the tank. 
The amount of fuel in the tank can now 
be read off from the <Node id="24257"/>vertical ascending 
pipe<Node id="24281"/>. 
For an exact indication the airplane must 
stand on level ground and the measuring 
device must be held vertically. 
The  designated  location  for  the  fuel 
quantity measuring device is a bag on the 
rear side of the <Node id="24504"/>pilot seat.<Node id="24515"/> 
  Page 7 - 46    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 349-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                             Airplane Description 
Fuel Temperature 
A fuel temperature sensor measures the fuel temperature in each main tank. The indication 
is provided by the G1000 flight display. Information about fuel temperature limitations 
can be found in Chapter 2 - OPERATING LIMITATIONS. 
The lower yellow bar indicates that the airplane is not ready for take-off if Diesel Fuel or 
a blend of Diesel Fuel with Jet Fuel is used (approved only if MÄM 42-037 is incorporated). 
If the fuel grade is uncertain, take-off is not allowed in this temperature range either. 
In the temperature range below -5 °C (23 °F) the engine must not be started if Diesel Fuel 
or a blend of Diesel Fuel with Jet Fuel is used. If the fuel blend is uncertain, the engine 
must not be started in this temperature range either. 
If the airplane is being operated with Jet Fuel, operation in the yellow temperature range 
is permissible. 
Fuel Grade 
Approved fuel grades are listed in Section 2.14 - FUEL. As the fuel grade is important 
concerning operating temperature limitations, the pilot must be sure about the fuel grade. 
Cold Diesel Fuel tends to flocculate, which can lead to clogging of the fuel filter. The fuel 
filter is not heated. 
If the airplane is operated in a cold environment, it must be changed from Diesel Fuel 
operation to Jet Fuel operation. To ensure that no blend of Jet Fuel with Diesel Fuel is 
in one of the tanks, each tank must be refilled at least twice with more than 65 liter 
(17.2 US gal) of Jet Fuel. Otherwise both tanks must be drained before refueling with 
Jet Fuel. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                          Page 7 - 47 
----------------------- Page 350-----------------------
Airplane Description                                                            DA 42 AFM 
                                           NOTE 
              In  order  to  provide  information  about  the  fuel  grade  it  is 
              recommended to enter the fuel grade in the airplane log each 
              time fuel is refilled. 
                                        CAUTION 
              If the airplane is operated with Diesel Fuel or a blend of Diesel 
              Fuel with Jet Fuel the use of the auxiliary tanks, if installed 
              (OÄM 42-056), is not permitted. 
 Page 7 - 48    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 351-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                          Airplane Description 
7.9.6  COOLING SYSTEM 
Each engine is liquid cooled. The liquid cooling system consists of a radiator and a bypass 
to this radiator. The bypass is in operation when coolant temperatures are low. It therefore 
allows the engine to warm-up quickly. Upon reaching a certain temperature (approximately 
88 °C or 190 °F) the radiator is activated by a thermostat valve. Additionally a coolant 
to air heat exchanger is provided for the cabin heat system. The flow through the heat 
exchanger is independent of the coolant temperature. An expansion tank helps to adjust 
the pressure in the system. The system is protected against over pressure by means of 
a pressure relief valve. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                        Page 7 - 49 
----------------------- Page 352-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                            DA 42 AFM 
7.9.7  OIL SYSTEMS 
Each engine has two separate oil systems. 
Lubrication System (Engine and Turbo-Charger) 
The engine lubrication is a wet sump lubrication system. The oil is cooled by a separate 
cooler on the underside of the engine. 
A dip-stick is provided to check the oil quantity through an inspection hole in the upper 
cowling. If required, oil can also be filled in there (for approved oil grades refer to Section 
2.4 - POWER-PLANT LIMITATIONS). 
Gearbox and Propeller Governor System 
The second oil circuit lubricates the gearbox and serves the governor system and the 
regulation of the propeller. 
The gearbox oil quantity can be checked with the help of an inspection glass which can 
be reached through an inspection hole on the front side of the lower cowling. 
                                         CAUTION 
               If  the  gearbox  oil  quantity  is  too  low,  an  unscheduled 
               maintenance is necessary (for approved oil grades refer to 
               Section 2.4 - POWER-PLANT LIMITATIONS). 
  Page 7 - 50    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                         Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 353-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                               Airplane Description 
7.9.8  TURBO-CHARGER SYSTEM 
                                                              engine 
                                                              air inlet 
                       intercooler 
                                                                           filter box 
                             turbine                                          air filter 
        engine                                                              alternate air valve 
                                                    charger 
                                                                           alternate air inlet 
         waste gate 
                                               exhaust 
The exhaust system contains a manifold which collects exhaust gases from the outlets 
of the cylinders and feeds them to the turbine of the turbo charger. Behind the turbine 
the exhaust gases are guided through the lower cowling to the exterior of the airplane. 
Excess exhaust gases bypass the turbine. The bypass is controlled by the ECU through 
the waste gate valve. A manifold pressure sensor behind the compressor allows the ECU 
to calculate the correct position of the waste gate valve. This prevents excessive manifold 
pressures at low density altitudes. The intake air is compressed in the compressor which 
is driven by the turbine, and is subsequently cooled down in the intercooler to increase 
power. Cooling the air increases efficiency through the higher density of the cooler air. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                           Page 7 - 51 
----------------------- Page 354-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                         DA 42 AFM 
7.9.9  FIRE DETECTION SYSTEM 
The fire detection system in the DA 42 consists of an overheat detector in the hot area 
of each engine. In case of an increase of the engine compartment temperature above 
250 °C (480 °F) the overheat detector closes the electric circuit and a warning message 
appears in the annunciation window of the G1000 PFD. 
To test the fire detectors (refer to Section 4A.6.1 - PREFLIGHT INSPECTION) push the 
test button located next to the gear selector switch. An aural alert and the fire warning 
message for the LH and RH engine should appear in the annunciation window of the 
G1000 PFD. 
                                        CAUTION 
               If  the  aural  alert  or  the  warning  does  not  appear,  an 
               unscheduled maintenance is necessary. 
  Page 7 - 52    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 355-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                              Airplane Description 
7.10  ELECTRICAL SYSTEM 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8      15-Dec-2017                  Page 7 - 53 
----------------------- Page 356-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                           DA 42 AFM 
7.10.1  GENERAL 
The DA 42 has 28 Volt DC system, which can be sub-divided into: 
      - Power generation 
      - Storage 
      - Distribution 
      - Consumers 
Power Generation 
Power generation is provided by two 60 Ampère alternators (generators) which are 
mounted on the bottom left side of each engine. The alternators are driven by a flat belt. 
The power output line of the left hand alternator is connected to the LH MAIN BUS via 
the LH alternator relay and a 70 Ampère circuit breaker. The power output line of the RH 
alternator is connected to the RH MAIN BUS via the RH alternator relay and a 70 Ampère 
circuit breaker. Both main busses are connected to the BATTERY BUS via a 90 Ampère 
circuit breaker. 
Both generator power output lines also run through a current sensor for each alternator, 
which provides an indication of the power being supplied to the electrical system by an 
alternator including the current for battery charging on the G1000. In the event of a main 
battery failure the field of each alternator is energized by two 12 V, 1.3 Ah sealed lead 
acid batteries (excitation battery) connected in series, which are installed in the nose 
baggage compartment. The ENGINE MASTER LH (RH) switches connect the excitation 
battery to the alternator field via a 5 Ampère fuse. 
If MÄM 42-240 or OÄM 42-074 or OÄM 42-129 are carried out: 
The ENGINE MASTER LH (RH) switches connect the excitation battery to the alternator 
field via a 10 Ampère fuse. 
  Page 7 - 54    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 357-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                         Airplane Description 
Alternator Control: 
Each alternator has an alternator control unit. It measures the alternator output voltage 
and controls the current through the alternator field coils via a pulse-width modulated 
signal. To keep the output voltage stable in all load and speed situations, the alternator 
field signal is modulated accordingly. 
The alternator control unit includes a comprehensive set of diagnostic functions that will 
warn the operator using a caution message (L/R ALTN FAIL) on the G1000 PFD in case 
of over- or undervoltage as well as a couple of other internal warning levels. 
Load balancing: The alternator  control unit supports  load balancing  across the two 
alternators via the internal alternator temperature. The temperature is measured and the 
alternator  control unit slightly decreases  alternator voltage output at higher internal 
alternator temperatures. Thus the load is partly shifted to the alternator with the lower 
internal temperature. This system is able to balance the actual load within a few amps 
between the two alternators installed. 
Storage 
Main battery power is stored in a 24 V, 10 Ah lead-acid battery mounted on the right-aft 
side of the front baggage compartment. The main battery is connected to the HOT 
BATTERY BUS and to the BATTERY BUS via the battery relay which is installed in the 
relay junction box on the center-aft side of the front baggage compartment. 
The battery relay is controlled with the ELECTRIC MASTER switch which is located on 
the left-hand side of the instrument panel. 
In addition, a non-rechargeable dry battery is installed as a further source of power for 
the attitude gyro (artificial horizon) and the flood light. When the EMERGENCY switch 
is set to ON, these two systems are supplied with power for at least 1.5 hours, independent 
of all other electrical consumers. During each 100 hour inspection, this battery is checked 
for proper functioning. Every 2 years or after use (broken seal on the switch) the battery 
package must be replaced. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                       Page 7 - 55 
----------------------- Page 358-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                       DA 42 AFM 
Distribution 
Electrical power is distributed via the HOT BATTERY BUS, the BATTERY BUS, the LH 
(RH) ECU BUS, the LH (RH) MAIN BUS, and the AVIONIC BUS. 
HOT BATTERY BUS: 
The HOT BATTERY BUS is directly connected to the MAIN BATTERY and cannot be 
disconnected from the MAIN BATTERY. The HOT BATTERY BUS provides power to 
the pilot map/reading light and ELT RCPI unit which are protected by there own fuses. 
BATTERY BUS: 
The BATTERY BUS is connected to the main battery via the battery relay which can be 
controlled by the ELECTRIC MASTER switch. The BATTERY BUS provides power to 
the LH (RH) MAIN BUS and heavy duty power to both starters. 
ECU BUS: 
The LH (RH) ECU BUS is connected to the LH (RH) MAIN BUS via a diode and connected 
to the power output line of the alternator via diode and a 30 Ampère circuit breaker and 
provides power for the ECU A and ECU B via the LH (RH) ECU A (B) relays which are 
controlled by the LH (RH) ENGINE MASTER switch. The LH (RH) ENGINE MASTER 
switch must be set to ON to connect the ECU A and ECU B to the ECU BUS. 
To support the alternator electrical power supply to the ECUs in case of a malfunction 
of the main battery, additional sealed-lead-acid batteries (ECU  backup battery) are 
connected to the RH and LH ECU BUS.  
If OÄM 42-129 is carried out: 
These batteries are able to provide 30 minutes of engine operation in case of a complete 
airplane electrical failure. Both engines may stop if the 30 minutes have elapsed. 
  Page 7 - 56    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 359-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                          Airplane Description 
MAIN BUS: 
The LH (RH) MAIN BUS is connected to the BATTERY BUS via a 90 Ampère circuit 
breaker. The LH MAIN BUS provides power to the consumers directly connected to the 
LH MAIN BUS. The RH MAIN BUS provides power to the consumers directly connected 
to the RH MAIN BUS and the AVIONIC BUS via the AVIONICS MASTER relay. 
The AVIONIC MASTER switch must be set to ON to connect the RH MAIN BUS to the 
AVIONIC BUS. 
Consumers 
The individual consumers (e.g. radio, position lights, etc.) are connected to the appropriate 
bus via automatic circuit breakers. 
Designations and abbreviations used to identify the circuit breakers are explained in 
Section 1.5 - DEFINITIONS AND ABBREVIATIONS. 
Voltmeter 
The voltmeter displays the voltage of the  electrical system. Under normal operating 
conditions the alternator voltage is shown, otherwise it displays the main battery voltage. 
Ammeter 
The ammeter displays the intensity of current which is supplied to the electrical system 
by the LH (RH) alternator. 
Landing and Taxi Lights 
Landing and taxi lights are built into the wing center section, and are each operated by 
means of a switch (LANDING, TAXI) located on the row of switches on the instrument 
panel. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Page 7 - 57 
----------------------- Page 360-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                          DA 42 AFM 
Position and Strobe Lights 
Combined position and strobe lights (anti collision lights) are installed on both wing tips. 
Each system is operated by a switch (POSITION, STROBE) located on the row of switches 
on the instrument panel. 
Flood Light 
A two-dimensional light emitter is mounted above the instrument panel. It illuminates the 
instrument panel as well as all levers, switches, etc. The flood light is switched on and 
its brightness is adjusted by means of a rotary button (FLOOD) in the LH section of the 
instrument panel. 
Instrument Lighting 
With a rotary button (INSTRUMENT) in the LH section of the instrument panel the internal 
lighting of the instruments is switched on and its brightness is adjusted. 
Pitot Heating 
The Pitot probe, which provides measurement for the Pitot-static system, is electrically 
heated. The heating is activated with a switch (PITOT HEAT) located on the row of 
switches on the instrument panel. The temperature is automatically kept constant by 
means of a thermal switch on the Pitot probe, and as an additional safety measure a 
thermal fuse is built in. If this thermal fuse is activated, the Pitot heating can no longer 
be switched on, and the PITOT HT fail will be displayed. In this case the system should 
be serviced. The PITOT HT OFF is on if the Pitot heating is switched off. 
  Page 7 - 58    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 361-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                       Airplane Description 
External Power Socket 
The DA 42 has an external 28 Volt DC power socket located on the lower surface of the 
fuselage nose section. When external power is connected, the control relay is energized 
and the external power comes online. 
The socket itself has three pins: 
   •  A large negative pin 
   •  A large positive pin 
   •  A small positive pin 
A diode protects the system from reverse polarity. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Page 7 - 59 
----------------------- Page 362-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                       DA 42 AFM 
7.10.2  ENGINE CONTROL UNIT / ECU 
Engine Control and Regulation 
The ECU monitors, controls and regulates all important parameters for engine operation. 
Sensors installed are: 
   -  Oil temperature (lubrication system engine) / OIL TEMP 
   -  Oil pressure (lubrication system engine) / OIL PRES 
  -   Coolant temperature / COOLANT TEMP 
  -   Gearbox temperature / GEARBOX 
  -   Camshaft RPM (twice) 
  -   Crankshaft RPM (twice) 
  -   Fuel pressure in the common rail 
  -   Manifold pressure 
  -   Manifold air temperature 
  -   Ambient air pressure 
  -   Propeller governor / oil pressure 
  -   Power lever position (twice) 
  -   Voltage 
  -   Starter switch signal 
  -   Fuel pressure 
  -   ECU SWAP switch signal 
  -   ECU TEST switch signal 
  Page 7 - 60    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                      Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 363-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                          Airplane Description 
In  accordance  with  the  received  signals  and  a  comparison  with  the  programmed 
characteristic  diagrams the necessary  inputs are calculated and transmitted by the 
following signal lines to the engine: 
   -  Activation of starter (relay) 
   -  Signal for propeller governor pressure valve 
   -  Signal for the rail-pressure regulation valve 
   -  Signal for each of the 4 injection nozzles  
   -  Activation of the glow plugs 
   -  Signal for the waste gate valve 
The following alerts are displayed on PFD of the G1000: 
   -  Glow sparks active 
   -  Status ECU A 
   -  Status ECU B 
Normally each engine is controlled and regulated by the appropriate ECU A. The ECU B 
is a backup system to ensure redundancy. In case of an internal error during operation 
or the loss of a sensor signal the system automatically switches to ECU B. If the loss of 
the sensor signal was the cause for the error, the system automatically switches back 
to ECU A. 
A fault in one of the ECUs is indicated by a caution message on the PFD (L/R ECU A/B 
FAIL). In case of minor faults, the annunciation can be reset once by pressing the ECU 
TEST button for more than 2 seconds. However, the annunciation will re-appear upon 
the next attempt to start the engine. After the indication of the L/R ECU A/B FAIL caution 
message, the engine must be serviced, even if the caution message could be reset. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Page 7 - 61 
----------------------- Page 364-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                           DA 42 AFM 
7.10.3  WARNING, CAUTION AND ADVISORY MESSAGES 
Crew Alerting System (CAS) 
The G1000 Crew Alerting System (CAS) is designed to provide visual and aural alerts 
to the flight crew. Alerts are divided into three levels as follows: 
                                        WARNING 
                                        CAUTION 
                                       ADVISORY 
Crew alerts will appear in the Alerts Window on the PFD. In this window warnings will 
appear at the top, followed by cautions and advisories, respectively. Within the criticality 
levels, messages will appear from newest (top) to oldest (bottom).  
At the low right corner of the display there is a MSG (message) soft key. The MSG key 
provides two functions in the CAS: 
1.  Pressing the MSG key acknowledges a new master warning / caution / advisory 
    indication. 
2.  An additional MSG key press with no master alert indication active will open a pop-up 
    Auxiliary Flight Display (AFD) page that contains information for all active alerts. 
This structure allows the crew to scroll through all system alerts if the Alerts Window 
overflows. This approach displays the most critical alerts close to the pilot’s primary field 
of view at all times, with the option of allowing lower criticality alerts to overflow and be 
accessible from the pop-up AFD page/window. 
  Page 7 - 62    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 365-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                     Airplane Description 
Alert Levels 
        Level              Text Color           Importance          Audible Tone 
                                                                    Warning chime 
                                                May require       tone which repeats 
       Warning                Red                immediate        without delay until 
                                              corrective action    acknowledged by 
                                                                       the crew 
                                             May require future     Single warning 
       Caution               Amber 
                                              corrective action      chime tone  
    Annunciation 
                             White                                       None 
      Advisory 
  Message Advisory           White                                       None 
   Safe Operation 
                             Green                Lowest                 None 
    Annunciation 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                      Page 7 - 63 
----------------------- Page 366-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                         DA 42 AFM 
Warning Alerts on the G1000 
  Warning Alerts                               Meaning / Cause 
                       The annunciation is active when the engine coolant temperature 
 L/R ENG TEMP 
                       is greater than 105 °C. 
                       The annunciation is active when the engine oil temperature is 
 L/R OIL TEMP 
                       greater than 140 °C. 
                       The annunciation is active when the engine oil pressure is less 
 L/R OIL PRES 
                       than 1 bar. 
                       The annunciation is active when the fuel temperature is greater 
 L/R FUEL TEMP 
                       than 75 °C. 
                       The annunciation is active when the gearbox oil temperature is 
 L/R GBOX TEMP 
                       greater than 120 °C. 
                       The annunciation is active when the alternator load is greater than 
 L/R ALTN AMPS 
                       60 amps. 
 L/R ENG FIRE          The annunciation is active when an engine fire is detected. 
                       This annunciation is used to indicate to the pilot that the starter 
 L/R STARTER 
                       is engaged when it should not be. 
                       The annunciation is used to indicate to the pilot if the baggage-, 
 DOOR OPEN 
                       canopy- or rear door is open. 
 POSN ERROR            The annunciation is active when the G1000 will no longer provide 
                       GPS based navigational guidance. 
 ATTITUDE FAIL         The  annunciation  is  active  when  the  display  system  is not 
                       receiving attitude reference information from the AHRS. 
 AIRSPEED FAIL         The  annunciation  is  active  when  the  display  system  is not 
                       receiving airspeed input from the air data computer. 
 ALTITUDE FAIL         The  annunciation  is  active  when  the  display  system  is not 
                       receiving altitude input from the air data computer. 
 VERT SPEED            The  annunciation  is  active  when  the  display  system  is  not 
 FAIL                  receiving vertical speed input from the air data computer. 
  Page 7 - 64    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 367-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                       Airplane Description 
  Warning Alerts                             Meaning / Cause 
 HDG                  The  annunciation  is  active  when  the  display  system  is  not 
                      receiving valid heading input from the AHRS. 
 WARN                 This annunciation constitutes a RAIM position warning. The nav 
                      deviation bar is removed. 
Audible Warning Alerts 
  Warning Alerts                             Meaning / Cause 
                      A  warning  chime  tone  which  repeats  without delay is  active 
 Landing Gear         when the landing gear is retracted while the flaps move into the 
 Retracted            LDG position or when the POWER lever is placed in a position 
                      below approx. 20 %. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Page 7 - 65 
----------------------- Page 368-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                              DA 42 AFM 
Caution Alerts on the G1000 
   Caution Alerts                                  Meaning / Cause 
                         The annunciation is active when a fault in ECU A or ECU B has 
 L/R ECU A FAIL          occurred. 
 or                      In case of minor faults, the annunciation can be reset once by 
                         pressing  the  ECU  TEST  button  for  more  than  2  seconds. 
 L/R ECU B FAIL          However, the annunciation will re-appear upon the next attempt 
                         to start the engine. 
                         The  annunciation  is  active  when  the  fuel  quantity  is  below 
 L/R FUEL LOW 
                         4 ± 1 US gal usable fuel. 
 L/R VOLTS LOW           The annunciation is active when bus voltage is less than 25 Volts. 
 L/R ALTN FAIL           The annunciation is active when the alternator has failed. 
 L/R COOL LVL            The annunciation is active when engine coolant level is low. 
 PITOT FAIL              The annunciation is active when the Pitot heater is failed. 
 PITOT HT OFF            The annunciation is active when the Pitot heat is off. 
 STAL HT FAIL            The annunciation is active when the stall heater is failed. 
 STAL HT OFF             The annunciation is active when the stall heater is off. 
 STICK LIMIT             Control stick limiting system (variable elevator stop) has failed. 
                         This annunciation can only occur when the auxiliary fuel tank 
                         system (optional) is installed. 
 L/R AUX FUEL E 
                         The annunciation is active when the L/R auxiliary fuel tank is 
                         empty and the FUEL TRANSFER pump is ON. 
 INTEG  RAIM  not        The annunciation is active when RAIM (Receiver Autonomous 
 available               Integrity Monitor) is not available. 
 AHRS        ALIGN:      The annunciation is active when the AHRS (Attitude and Heading 
 Keep Wings Level        Reference System) is aligning. 
 CHECK  GEAR             Landing gear is not down and locked. 
 (if installed) 
  Page 7 - 66    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                          Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 369-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                     Airplane Description 
Annunciation Advisory Alerts on the G1000 
  Advisory Alerts                            Meaning / Cause 
 L/R GLOW ON          The annunciation is active when the glow plugs are powered. 
 L/R FUEL XFER        The annunciation is active when fuel transfer from auxiliary to 
                      main tank is in progress. 
Message Advisory Alerts on the G1000 
  Advisory Alerts                            Meaning / Cause 
 PFD FAN FAIL         The annunciation is active when the PFD fan is inoperative. 
 MFD FAN FAIL         The annunciation is active when the MFD fan is inoperative. 
 GIA FAN FAIL         The annunciation is active when the GIA fan is inoperative. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8      15-Dec-2017                      Page 7 - 67 
----------------------- Page 370-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                             DA 42 AFM 
7.11  PITOT-STATIC SYSTEM 
Total pressure is measured at the leading edge of a Pitot probe under the left wing. Static 
pressure is measured at two orifices at the lower and rear edges of the same probe. To 
protect against dirt and condensation there are filters in the system, which are accessible 
from the wing root. The Pitot probe is electrically heated. 
With the alternate static valve, the static pressure in the cabin can be used as static 
pressure source in the event of a failure of the Pitot-static system. 
If an autopilot system is installed, additional static sources may be installed. 
7.12  STALL WARNING SYSTEM 
The lift detector of the DA 42 is located on the front edge of the left wing below the wing 
chord line. It is supplied electrically and provides a stall warning, before the angle of attack 
becomes critical. The stall status is announced to the pilot by a continuous sound in the 
cockpit. 
The lift detector vane, the mounting plate and the complete housing are heated to prevent 
icing. Heating is engaged together with the Pitot heating. 
  Page 7 - 68    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                         Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 371-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                             Airplane Description 
7.13  GARMIN G1000 INTEGRATED AVIONICS SYSTEM 
7.13.1  GENERAL 
The Gamin G1000 is a fully integrated flight, engine, communication, navigation and 
surveillance instrumentation system. This Integrated Avionics System consists of a Primary 
Flight Display (PFD), a Multifunction Display (MFD), an Audio Panel, an Attitude and 
Heading Reference System (AHRS), an Air Data Computer (ADC) and the sensors and 
computers to process flight and engine information for display to the pilot. The system 
contains  dual  GPS  receivers,  dual  VOR/ILS  receivers,  dual  VHF  communications 
transceivers, a transponder, and an integrated annunciation system to alert the pilot of 
certain abnormal conditions. 
A remote avionic box is located behind the aft baggage compartment frame. A push-to-talk 
(PTT) button for the COM portion of the G1000 is mounted on the end of each control 
stick. There are connection facilities for up to 4 headsets between the front seats. 
Refer to the Garmin G1000 Cockpit Reference Guide, Garmin P/N 190-00406-( ), latest 
effective issue and Pilot s Guide, P/N 190-00649-( ), latest effective issue for complete 
descriptions of the G1000 system and operating procedures. 
                                            NOTE 
                Near the DME ground station, it can happen under certain 
               adverse conditions that the Bendix/King KN 63 DME loses 
               the direct signal from the ground station and locks onto an 
                "echo".  This  will  result  in  an  inaccurate  indication  of  the 
               distance. 
                                            NOTE 
                During  retraction  and  extension  of  the  landing  gear  the 
               ADF-indication may be inaccurate. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                          Page 7 - 69 
----------------------- Page 372-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                          DA 42 AFM 
7.13.2  PRIMARY FLIGHT DISPLAY (PFD) 
The Primary Flight Display (PFD; see Figure below) typically displays airspeed, attitude, 
altitude, and heading information in a traditional format. Slip information is shown as a 
trapezoid under the bank pointer. One width of the trapezoid is equal to a one ball width 
slip. Rate of turn information is shown on the scale above the compass rose; full scale 
deflection is equal to a standard rate turn. The following controls are available on the PFD 
(clockwise from top right): 
*   Communications frequency volume and squelch knob 
*   Communications frequency set knobs 
*   Communications frequency transfer button 
*   Altimeter setting knob (baro set) 
*   Course knob 
*   Map range knob and cursor control 
*   FMS control buttons and knob 
*   PFD softkey buttons, including master warning/caution acknowledgment 
*   Altitude reference set knob 
*   Heading bug control 
*   Navigation frequency transfer button 
*   Navigation frequency set knobs 
*   Navigation frequency volume and Identifier knob 
  Page 7 - 70    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 373-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                        Airplane Description 
The PFD displays the crew alerting (annunciator) system. When a warning or caution 
message is received, a warning or caution annunciator will flash on the PFD, accompanied 
by an aural tone. A  warning is accompanied by a repeating tone, and a caution is 
accompanied by a single tone. Acknowledging the alert will cancel the flashing and provide 
a text description of the message. Refer to Chapter 3 - EMERGENCY PROCEDURES, 
Chapter 4B - ABNORMAL OPERATING PROCEDURES, and Section 7.10.3 - WARNING, 
CAUTION AND ADVISORY LIGHTS. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                        Page 7 - 71 
----------------------- Page 374-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                             DA 42 AFM 
Advisory  messages  related  to  G1000  system  status  are  shown  in  white  and  are 
accompanied by a white flashing ADVISORY alert. Refer to the G1000 Pilot s Guide and 
Cockpit Reference Guide for descriptions of the messages and recommended actions 
(if applicable). 
Trend vectors are shown on the airspeed and altimeter displays as a magenta line 
predicting 6 seconds at the current rate. The turn rate indicator also functions as a trend 
indicator on the compass scale. 
The PFD can be displayed in a composite format for emergency use by pressing the 
DISPLAY BACKUP button on the audio panel. In the composite mode, the full crew alerting 
function remains, but no map functions are available. 
7.13.3  MULTI-FUNCTION DISPLAY (MFD) 
The Multi-Function Display (MFD) typically displays engine data, maps, terrain, traffic 
and topography displays, and flight planning and progress information. The display unit 
is identical to the PFD and contains the same controls as previously listed. 
Engine instruments are displayed on the MFD. Discrete engine sensor information is 
processed by the Garmin Engine Airframe (GEA) sub-system. When an engine sensor 
indicates a value outside the normal operating range, the legend will turn yellow for caution 
range, and turn red and flash for warning range. 
Also refer to Section 7.9.4 - ENGINE INSTRUMENTS. 
  Page 7 - 72    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                         Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 375-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                           Airplane Description 
7.13.4  AUDIO PANEL 
The audio panel contains traditional transmitter and receiver selectors, as well as an 
integral intercom and marker beacon system. The marker beacon lights appear on the 
PFD. In addition, a clearance recorder records the last 2 ½ minutes of received audio. 
Lights above the selections indicate what selections are active. Pressing the red DISPLAY 
BACKUP button on the audio panel causes both the PFD and MFD to display a composite 
mode. 
7.13.5  ATTITUDE AND HEADING REFERENCE SYSTEM (AHRS) 
The Attitude and Heading Reference System (AHRS) uses GPS, rate sensors, air data, 
and magnetic variation to determine pitch and roll attitude, sideslip and heading. Operation 
is possible in a degraded mode if the system loses any of these inputs. Status messages 
alert the crew of the loss of any of these inputs. The AHRS will align while the airplane 
is in motion, but will align quicker if the wings are kept level during the alignment process. 
7.13.6  AIR DATA COMPUTER (ADC) 
The  Air  Data  Computer  (ADC)  provides  airspeed,  altitude,  vertical  speed,  and  air 
temperature to the display system. In addition to the primary displays, this information 
is used by the FMS and TIS systems. 
7.13.7 GWX 68 WEATHER RADAR 
The Garmin GWX 68 Weather Radar System provides information about precipitation 
conditions ahead of the airplane. The system consists of a combined microwave transmitter 
and receiver system in the nose cone, mounted to the front baggage compartment 
bulkhead. The system is connected to the electrical system of the airplane via a circuit 
breaker on the instrument panel. The processed data of the GWX 68 system is displayed 
on the Garmin G1000 MFD. Refer to the Garmin G1000 Pilot’s Guide, P/N 190-00649-( ), 
latest effective issue for more information. 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                         Page 7 - 73 
----------------------- Page 376-----------------------
 Airplane Description                                                         DA 42 AFM 
7.14  STRUCTURAL TEMPERATURE INDICATOR 
If OÄM 42-188 is carried out a structural temperature indicator, installed in the LH and 
RH main landing gear bay (see Figure below) indicates when the structural temperature 
limitation is exceeded (refer to Section 2.16.10). The indicator needs to be checked if the 
zero fuel mass exceeds 1650 kg (3638 lb). 
At temperatures below the 55°C (131°F) limit, the indicator appears all red with a faint 
indication of "55" (°C). At temperatures exceeding the 55°C (131°F) limit, the indicator 
displays a clearly contrasting red "55" (°C) on a black background (see Figure below). 
                                          NOTE 
               At temperatures approaching the limit, the background will 
               progressively darken prior to turning black; this indicates 
               acceptable temperatures. 
A red "55" on black background indicates that the structural temperature limit is exceeded. 
In this case the maximum zero fuel mass is 1650 kg (3638 lb): 
  Page 7 - 74    Rev. 8       15-Dec-2017                       Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 377-----------------------
 DA 42 AFM                                                  Airplane Description 
Location of Temperature Indicator and Placard 
LH MLG bay shown, RH MLG bay opposite: 
  Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8      15-Dec-2017                    Page 7 - 75 
----------------------- Page 378-----------------------
Airplane Description                                                            DA 42 AFM 
                                  Intentionally left blank. 
 Page 7 - 76    Rev. 8        15-Dec-2017                        Doc. No. 7.01.05-E 
----------------------- Page 379-----------------------
                                                                                       Handling, Care, 
DA 42 AFM 
                                                                                           Maintenance 
                                          CHAPTER 8 
 AIRPLANE HANDLING, CARE AND MAINTENANCE 
                                                                                                       Page 
        8.1     INTRODUCTION __________________________________________________________ 8-2 
        8.2     AIRPLANE INSPECTION INTERVALS                  _________________________________8-2 
        8.3     AIRPLANE ALTERATIONS OR REPAIRS  ______________________________8-3 
        8.4     SERVICING ________________________________________________________________ 8-3 
                8.4.1  REFUELING  _________________________________________________________8-3 
                8.4.2  ENGINE OIL LEVEL CHECK            _____________________________________ 8-5 
                8.4.3  GEARBOX OIL LEVEL CHECK               __________________________________ 8-6 
                8.4.4  TIRE INFLATION PRESSURE CHECK                     _________________________ 8-6 
        8.5     GROUND HANDLING / ROAD TRANSPORT                         _________________________ 8-7 
                8.5.1  GROUND HANDLING         _____________________________________________8-7 
                8.5.2  PARKING __________________________________________________________ 8-10 
                8.5.3  MOORING _________________________________________________________8-13 
                8.5.4  JACKING __________________________________________________________ 8-13 
        8.6     CLEANING AND CARE       _________________________________________________ 8-14 
                8.6.1  PAINTED SURFACES         ___________________________________________ 8-14 
                8.6.2  CANOPY AND REAR DOOR               ____________________________________8-14 
                8.6.3  PROPELLER  ______________________________________________________8-15 
                8.6.4  ENGINE ____________________________________________________________8-15 
                8.6.5  INTERIOR SURFACES          __________________________________________8-15 
        8.7     GROUND DE-ICING ______________________________________________________8-16 
 Doc. No. 7.01.05-E    Rev. 8            15-Dec-2017                              Page 8 - 1 
----------------------- Page 380-----------------------
 Handling, Care, 
                                                                             DA 42 AFM 
<Node id="67268"/></TextWithNodes>
<!-- The default annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet>
<Annotation Id="1" Type="Mention" StartNode="1676" EndNode="1686">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/propellers-1</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="2" Type="Mention" StartNode="1736" EndNode="1742">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/blades-2</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="3" Type="Mention" StartNode="1774" EndNode="1781">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/coating-3</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="4" Type="Mention" StartNode="1802" EndNode="1806">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/edge-4</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="5" Type="Mention" StartNode="2104" EndNode="2107">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/ECU-5</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="6" Type="Mention" StartNode="2173" EndNode="2186">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/propeller-hub-6</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="7" Type="Mention" StartNode="2246" EndNode="2251">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/valve-7</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="8" Type="Mention" StartNode="2258" EndNode="2272">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/governor-valve-8</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="9" Type="Mention" StartNode="2823" EndNode="2843">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Pressure-Accumulator-9</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="10" Type="Mention" StartNode="2946" EndNode="2960">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/electric-valve-10</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="11" Type="Mention" StartNode="2968" EndNode="2979">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/accumulator-11</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="12" Type="Mention" StartNode="3008" EndNode="3029">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/ENGINE-MASTER-switch-12</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="13" Type="Mention" StartNode="3328" EndNode="3344">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/gearbox-oil-pump-13</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="14" Type="Mention" StartNode="3670" EndNode="3693">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/electric-governor-valve-14</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="15" Type="Mention" StartNode="5610" EndNode="5621">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/POWER-Lever-15</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="16" Type="Mention" StartNode="6434" EndNode="6452">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/propeller-governor-16</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="17" Type="Mention" StartNode="6481" EndNode="6484">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/ECU-17</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="18" Type="Mention" StartNode="6592" EndNode="6608">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/gearbox-oil-pump-18</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="19" Type="Mention" StartNode="6711" EndNode="6717">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/blades-19</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="20" Type="Mention" StartNode="10708" EndNode="10718">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/air-filter-20</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="21" Type="Mention" StartNode="10770" EndNode="10788">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/engine-compartment-21</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="22" Type="Mention" StartNode="14482" EndNode="14487">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/tanks-22</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="23" Type="Mention" StartNode="14513" EndNode="14518">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/wings-23</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="24" Type="Mention" StartNode="14543" EndNode="14555">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/right-engine-24</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="25" Type="Mention" StartNode="14585" EndNode="14594">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/main-tank-25</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="26" Type="Mention" StartNode="14720" EndNode="14729">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/cylinders-26</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="27" Type="Mention" StartNode="14735" EndNode="14753">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/injection-nozzles-27</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="28" Type="Mention" StartNode="14803" EndNode="14814">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/common-rail-28</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="29" Type="Mention" StartNode="14906" EndNode="14923">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/low-pressure-pump-29</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="30" Type="Mention" StartNode="14996" EndNode="14999">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/ECU-30</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="31" Type="Mention" StartNode="15012" EndNode="15026">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/electric-valve-31</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="32" Type="Mention" StartNode="15203" EndNode="15218">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/crossfeed-lines-32</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="33" Type="Mention" StartNode="15237" EndNode="15244">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/nacelle-33</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="34" Type="Mention" StartNode="15248" EndNode="15267">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/auxiliary-fuel-tank-34</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="35" Type="Mention" StartNode="15587" EndNode="15606">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/fuel-selector-valve-35</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="36" Type="Mention" StartNode="15624" EndNode="15638">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/control-levers-36</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="37" Type="Mention" StartNode="15648" EndNode="15668">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/uel-selector-valves-37</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="38" Type="Mention" StartNode="18648" EndNode="18663">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Main-Fuel-Tanks-38</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="39" Type="Mention" StartNode="18693" EndNode="18710">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/aluminum-chambers-39</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="40" Type="Mention" StartNode="18736" EndNode="18749">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/flexible-hose-40</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="41" Type="Mention" StartNode="18781" EndNode="18787">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/filler-41</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="42" Type="Mention" StartNode="18972" EndNode="18982">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/tank-vents-42</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="43" Type="Mention" StartNode="18999" EndNode="19010">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/check-valve-43</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="44" Type="Mention" StartNode="19048" EndNode="19069">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/relief-pressure-valve-44</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="45" Type="Mention" StartNode="19349" EndNode="19358">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/capillary-45</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="46" Type="Mention" StartNode="19608" EndNode="19621">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/coarse-filter-46</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="47" Type="Mention" StartNode="19711" EndNode="19723">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/outlet-valve-47</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="48" Type="Mention" StartNode="20000" EndNode="20008">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/firewall-48</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="49" Type="Mention" StartNode="20203" EndNode="20208">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/G1000-49</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="50" Type="Mention" StartNode="21064" EndNode="21077">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/finger-filter-50</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="51" Type="Mention" StartNode="20540" EndNode="20560">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Auxiliary-Fuel-Tanks-51</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="52" Type="Mention" StartNode="20795" EndNode="20805">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/filler-cap-52</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="53" Type="Mention" StartNode="21158" EndNode="21176">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/fuel-transfer-pump-53</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="54" Type="Mention" StartNode="21283" EndNode="21297">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/solenoid-valve-54</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="55" Type="Mention" StartNode="21305" EndNode="21316">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/check-valve-55</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="56" Type="Mention" StartNode="21487" EndNode="21497">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/capillary--56</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="57" Type="Mention" StartNode="21631" EndNode="21647">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/fuel-drain-valve-57</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="58" Type="Mention" StartNode="21774" EndNode="21793">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/fuel-transfer-pumps-58</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="59" Type="Mention" StartNode="21266" EndNode="21279">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/inline-filter-59</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="60" Type="Mention" StartNode="21426" EndNode="21435">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/vent-line-60</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="61" Type="Mention" StartNode="21711" EndNode="21733">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/FUEL-TRANSFER-switches-61</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="62" Type="Mention" StartNode="15933" EndNode="15937">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/tank-62</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="63" Type="Mention" StartNode="21811" EndNode="21826">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/solenoid-valves-63</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="64" Type="Mention" StartNode="21832" EndNode="21840">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/switches-64</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="65" Type="Mention" StartNode="21864" EndNode="21883">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/elevator-trim-wheel-65</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="66" Type="Mention" StartNode="22069" EndNode="22088">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/auxiliary-fuel-tank-66</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="67" Type="Mention" StartNode="22106" EndNode="22120">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/main-fuel-tank-67</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="68" Type="Mention" StartNode="22335" EndNode="22348">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Garmin-G1000-68</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="69" Type="Mention" StartNode="23946" EndNode="23976">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/fuel-quantity-measuring-device-69</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="70" Type="Mention" StartNode="24048" EndNode="24058">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/tank-drain-70</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="71" Type="Mention" StartNode="24021" EndNode="24025">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/wing-71</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="72" Type="Mention" StartNode="24136" EndNode="24151">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/metal-connector-72</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="73" Type="Mention" StartNode="24257" EndNode="24281">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/vertical-ascending-pipe-73</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
<Annotation Id="74" Type="Mention" StartNode="24504" EndNode="24515">
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">class</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/Component</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">ontology</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea</Value>
</Feature>
<Feature>
  <Name className="java.lang.String">inst</Name>
  <Value className="java.lang.String">http://onto.fel.cvut.cz/ontologies/fmea/pilot-seat--74</Value>
</Feature>
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

<!-- Named annotation set -->

<AnnotationSet Name="Original markups">
<Annotation Id="0" Type="paragraph" StartNode="1" EndNode="67268">
</Annotation>
</AnnotationSet>

</GateDocument>

